<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>terraform on</title><link>http://wcollins.io/tags/terraform/</link><description>Recent content in terraform on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 07:44:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/tags/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 3)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-3/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 07:44:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-3/</guid><description>Check out Part 1 and Part 2 where we put together a scalable foundation and connect cloud networks from AWS, Azure, and GCP. For Part 3, we will bring on-premises back into the spotlight and connect some sites over Cisco SD-WAN and IPSEC.
On-premises remains a strong focus for many enterprises through 2021 going into 2022. Some workloads, as noted by Amazon CEO Andy Jassy, may never move to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 2)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 09:26:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we started with a scalable foundation that can adapt over time as the business grows and adjusts to changing markets. With Alkira&amp;rsquo;s Network Cloud, we take a cloud native approach in enabling our customer&amp;rsquo;s transformation. No appliances need to be provisioned in remote VPCs or VNets, and no agents need to be installed on workloads. Getting started is as easy as kicking off a build pipeline. For Part 2, let&amp;rsquo;s connect some networks from AWS, Azure, and GCP.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform - (Part 1)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 08:43:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-1/</guid><description>HashiCorp&amp;rsquo;s Terraform needs no introduction. It is all but the de facto vehicle for delivering cloud infrastructure, and for a good reason. What Terraform did for Multi-Cloud Infrastructure as Code, is precisely what Alkira does for the network. What happens when you use these two platforms together to deliver networking in and across clouds? If providing network services in code faster than ever before sounds interesting, this multi-part series is for you.</description></item><item><title>Intro To Terraform Modules With AWS</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/intro-to-terraform-modules-with-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 08:46:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/intro-to-terraform-modules-with-aws/</guid><description>Effectively automating infrastructure is no longer a luxury but a staple in the enterprise move through future transformation. I wrote a blog recently about using Terraform with Packer together, and wanted to take this thought further with breaking down Terraform Modules and getting well connected with Terraform Cloud. I recently put together a simple module for building base infrastructure in AWS for the purpose of testing Alkira Network Cloud. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!</description></item><item><title>Cloud Grade Automation With Packer and Terraform</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cloud-grade-automation-with-packer-and-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 12:32:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cloud-grade-automation-with-packer-and-terraform/</guid><description>Manually provisioning infrastructure slows down application delivery, isolates knowledge, can hamper operations teams, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale. Automating infrastructure provisioning can address these challenges by shifting manual process into code. Hashicorp has products spanning the infrastructure, security, and application stack that can unlock that cloud operating model and deliver applications faster.
Let&amp;rsquo;s examine image lifecycle management and IaaS deployment. Both of these tasks are common challenges faced by the enterprise when moving to the cloud.</description></item></channel></rss>