<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>netdevops - Category - Blog</title><link>http://wcollins.io/categories/netdevops/</link><description>netdevops - Category - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 13:42:35 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/categories/netdevops/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraforming Alkira and Fortinet is Multicloud Bliss</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/terraforming-alkira-and-fortinet-is-multicloud-bliss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 13:42:35 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/terraforming-alkira-and-fortinet-is-multicloud-bliss/</guid><description>There is a reason why enterprises prefer the best-of-breed approach to connect and secure their network and intellectual property. Alkira announced its integration with Fortinet at AWS re:Inforce in July, and this is a perfect example of the best in action. As anyone that reads my blog knows, I have an automation first approach to everything. Alkira&amp;rsquo;s Terraform Provider is Fortinet ready, so let&amp;rsquo;s take it for a spin!
Intro Key FeaturesThis partnership comes packed with great features, including the seamless integration of FortiManager (which orchestrates the Fortinet Security Fabric), extending existing firewall zones into and across clouds with auto-mapping of zones-to-groups, and weathering traffic surges with auto-scaling.</description></item><item><title>AnsibleFest 2020 - Automating IPAM In Cloud</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2020/automating-cloud-ipam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 07:16:08 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2020/automating-cloud-ipam/</guid><description>AnsibleFest AnsibleFest 2020, like most conferences this year, took place completely virtual. I presented on Automating IPAM In Cloud: Ansible + Netbox. You can find the slides along with the demonstration code in this git repo. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to expand a little further on the content I presented.
What is IPAM?IP Address Management (IPAM) is the critical component that organizes your IP addresses and networks in one place.</description></item><item><title>Automating Blog Releases: Hugo + GitHub Actions</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2020/automate-blog-deployment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 17:14:44 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2020/automate-blog-deployment/</guid><description>A lot of the work I do professionally involves transforming traditional network culture, practices, and technology. Just as DevOps transformed application delivery, NetDevOps is here to make sure the network can keep up. This post will cover how I deploy this blog with Hugo to GitHub Pages using GitHub Actions to completely automate the workflow. This is very similar to how I approached modernizing network documentation for my current employer. Listen to Day Two Cloud Podcast as I talk through this transformation in more detail.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Ansible (AWX) On Debian</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2020/setup-awx-on-debian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 12:29:55 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2020/setup-awx-on-debian/</guid><description>Ansible Tower VS AWXThe best way to learn is by constructing your own knowledge, not passively absorbing information. A lot of great projects are open source these days, including The AWX Project. At zero cost, you can build your automation skill set, increasing your chances at landing that next big promotion.
This post will cover how to setup Ansible AWX on Debian. I use a combination of Ansible and Terraform in the NetDevOps toolchain.</description></item></channel></rss>