<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>events - Category - Blog</title><link>http://wcollins.io/categories/events/</link><description>events - Category - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 14:25:04 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/categories/events/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Looking Back At 2022</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/looking-back-at-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 14:25:04 -0500</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/looking-back-at-2022/</guid><description>At the end of each year, I take some time for self-reflection. Looking back through 2022 gave me a colossal reminder of how vital teams, communities, and leaders are. Take hockey for instance. You have certain athletes, often referred to as generational players that carry unmatched individual talent and get selected first overall in the NHL Draft.
These players are weekly highlight reels, yet, without the right system, coaches, and team, they will never lift the Stanley Cup.</description></item><item><title>AWS re:Invent 2022 - Recap</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/aws-reinvent-2022-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 08:43:14 -0500</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/aws-reinvent-2022-recap/</guid><description>As far as tech conferences are concerned, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to find one as exciting as AWS re:Invent. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s anticipation for new product announcements or connecting in person with the community, there is something electrifying about being at ground zero. And if you can make the trip, you will get a lot of great exercise too! I hit close to 100K steps or approx. 43 miles according to my Fitbit. What were some of my favorite highlights from re:Invent 2022?</description></item><item><title>AWS Community Day - Midwest</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/aws-community-day-midwest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 06:34:18 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/aws-community-day-midwest/</guid><description>I had the opportunity to present at the 4th annual AWS Community Day for the Midwest in June. This event was planned, organized, and delivered by AWS user group leaders and was an absolute blast. I got to catch up with a few remarkable individuals I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked to since pre-pandemic, and I got to meet many new people and listen to their stories of transformation in their respective enterprises.</description></item></channel></rss>