<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>economics - Category - Blog</title><link>http://wcollins.io/categories/economics/</link><description>economics - Category - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:25:07 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/categories/economics/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Ripple Effect: Could Taxing Unrealized Gains Stifle Innovation?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:25:07 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/</guid><description>In my previous blog on Dilution of Ownership, I explored how startup funding rounds impact equity. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into a hot-button, highly-debated, and dramatically misunderstood matter of policy - taxing unrealized capital gains (or the wealth tax). Could this policy drastically alter the startup landscape? Would there be a tangible impact on founders, investors, and the innovation ecosystem as a whole?
Intro The Allure of Taxing Paper WealthOn the surface, taxing unrealized gains - (the increase in value of an asset that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been sold yet) - might seem like a fair way to ensure the ultra-wealthy pay their &amp;ldquo;fair share.</description></item><item><title>Cryptocurrency, Energy, and Proof-of-Stake</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/crypto-energy-efficiency-and-proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 15:41:42 -0800</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/crypto-energy-efficiency-and-proof-of-stake/</guid><description>New to cryptocurrency? Check this out for a quick primer. One of the giant debates, often a significant source of criticism, is Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s energy efficiency (or lack thereof). This criticism may also be expanded to any other currency, or blockchain backed technology that leverages proof-of-work as a consensus mechanism. Innovation is inherent in technology. New ideas, methods, and optimizations come along to take something, add new features, and make it more efficient.</description></item><item><title>Understanding The World Of Bitcoin</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/understanding-the-world-of-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 17:02:04 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/understanding-the-world-of-bitcoin/</guid><description>This is going to be a gigantic pivot from my usual topics of writing. If you are interested in learning something about cryptocurrency, stay put. The goal is to make this unbiased and thought-provoking while shedding light on what seems like a world of confusion and misinformation.
In the past month, I have heard various first-hand opinions about Bitcoin like, it is a pyramid scheme, basically gambling, will supersede the U.</description></item></channel></rss>