<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Business on William Collins</title><link>https://wcollins.io/categories/business/</link><description>Recent content in Business on William Collins</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2026 William Collins</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:32:36 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wcollins.io/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Are You Building AI Or Just Using It</title><link>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/are-you-building-ai-or-just-using-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 13:32:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/are-you-building-ai-or-just-using-it/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As AI dominates tech headlines and corporate strategies in 2024, an important distinction is being blurred - the difference between developing AI versus consuming AI services. This mischaracterization risks confusing the market and overselling capabilities, but that isn&amp;rsquo;t anything new right? Take zero-trust, cloud computing, or even take a look back at the &lt;em&gt;early-2000s&lt;/em&gt; with the web revolution. &lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ubaumannch/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"&gt;Urs Baumann&lt;/a&gt; tossed out a great questions in the &lt;em&gt;Network Automation Forum - Slack&lt;/em&gt; recently, and I thought it would make for a good blog &lt;em&gt;(or maybe venting session depending on how you look at it)&lt;/em&gt;. Remember, these are opinions.&lt;/p&gt;</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/are-you-building-ai-or-just-using-it/featured.png"/></item><item><title>The Ripple Effect: Could Taxing Unrealized Gains Stifle Innovation?</title><link>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:25:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"&gt;previous blog on Dilution of Ownership&lt;/a&gt;, I explored how startup funding rounds impact equity. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into a hot-button, highly-debated, and dramatically misunderstood matter of policy - taxing unrealized capital gains &lt;em&gt;(or the wealth tax)&lt;/em&gt;. Could this policy drastically alter the startup landscape? Would there be a tangible impact on founders, investors, and the innovation ecosystem as a whole?&lt;/p&gt;</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Understanding Dilution of Ownership</title><link>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 16:48:03 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of confusion surrounding the &lt;em&gt;dilution of ownership&lt;/em&gt;, especially in the tech startup space. What does this mean in &lt;em&gt;layman&amp;rsquo;s terms&lt;/em&gt;? Who does it impact? And most importantly, why you should care if you plan to work for a startup. This is a topic I have discussed with many new &lt;em&gt;(and even some seasoned)&lt;/em&gt; engineers over the past few years. I recently had this very discussion with a senior engineer &lt;em&gt;(and close friend)&lt;/em&gt; who is leaving big enterprise for startup land. He suggested I write a blog in the &lt;em&gt;plain speak&lt;/em&gt; that I used with him. Little does he know (until now) that this is as deep as I go on this topic!&lt;/p&gt;</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Cryptocurrency, Energy, and Proof-of-Stake</title><link>https://wcollins.io/posts/2021/crypto-energy-efficiency-and-proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 15:41:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>https://wcollins.io/posts/2021/crypto-energy-efficiency-and-proof-of-stake/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;New to &lt;em&gt;cryptocurrency&lt;/em&gt;? &lt;a href="https://wcollins.io/posts/2021/understanding-the-world-of-bitcoin/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"&gt;Check this out&lt;/a&gt; for a quick primer. One of the giant debates, often a significant source of criticism, is &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitcoin" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"&gt;Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; energy efficiency &lt;em&gt;(or lack thereof)&lt;/em&gt;. This criticism may also be expanded to any other currency, or &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blockchain" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"&gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt; backed technology that leverages &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Proof_of_work" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"&gt;proof-of-work&lt;/a&gt; as a consensus mechanism. Innovation is &lt;em&gt;inherent&lt;/em&gt; in technology. New ideas, methods, and optimizations come along to take something, add new features, and make it more efficient. One such optimization is &lt;em&gt;proof-of-stake&lt;/em&gt; which brings a greener look to consensus. How much can it help?&lt;/p&gt;</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://wcollins.io/posts/2021/crypto-energy-efficiency-and-proof-of-stake/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Understanding The World Of Bitcoin</title><link>https://wcollins.io/posts/2021/understanding-the-world-of-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 17:02:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wcollins.io/posts/2021/understanding-the-world-of-bitcoin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is going to be a gigantic pivot from my usual topics of writing. If you are interested in learning something about &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cryptocurrency" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"&gt;cryptocurrency&lt;/a&gt;, stay put. The goal is to make this unbiased and thought-provoking while shedding light on what seems like a world of confusion and misinformation.&lt;/p&gt;</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://wcollins.io/posts/2021/understanding-the-world-of-bitcoin/featured.png"/></item></channel></rss>