<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>netsecops on</title><link>http://wcollins.io/categories/netsecops/</link><description>Recent content in netsecops on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 13:42:35 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/categories/netsecops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Terraforming Alkira and Fortinet is Multicloud Bliss</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/terraforming-alkira-and-fortinet-is-multicloud-bliss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 13:42:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/terraforming-alkira-and-fortinet-is-multicloud-bliss/</guid><description>There is a reason why enterprises prefer the best-of-breed approach to connect and secure their network and intellectual property. Alkira announced its integration with Fortinet at AWS re:Inforce in July, and this is a perfect example of the best in action. As anyone that reads my blog knows, I have an automation first approach to everything. Alkira&amp;rsquo;s Terraform Provider is Fortinet ready, so let&amp;rsquo;s take it for a spin!
Key Features This partnership comes packed with great features, including the seamless integration of FortiManager (which orchestrates the Fortinet Security Fabric), extending existing firewall zones into and across clouds with auto-mapping of zone-to-segments, and weathering traffic surges with auto-scaling.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 4)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 15:10:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-4/</guid><description>In Part 1, we laid out our foundation. In Part 2 and Part 3 we connected various networks (both cloud and on-premises) and provisioned NGFWs that scale to real-time capacity. By default, networks connected to our corporate segment have full-mesh connectivity to each other. Let&amp;rsquo;s build some policies in code that can work with the groups we created to produce logical micro-segmentation that mirror a few real-world use cases.
Your browser does not support video.</description></item></channel></rss>