<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>multi cloud on</title><link>http://wcollins.io/categories/multi-cloud/</link><description>Recent content in multi cloud on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 07:53:57 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/categories/multi-cloud/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 3)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 07:53:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-3/</guid><description>Check out Part 1 and Part 2 where we put together a scalable foundation and connect cloud networks from AWS, Azure, and GCP. For Part 3, we will bring on-premises back into the spotlight and connect some sites over Cisco SD-WAN and IPSEC.
On-premises remains a strong focus for many enterprises through 2021 going into 2022. Some workloads, as noted by Amazon CEO Andy Jassy, may never move to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 2)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 09:26:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we started with a scalable foundation that can adapt over time as the business grows and adjusts to changing markets. With Alkira&amp;rsquo;s Network Cloud, we take a cloud native approach in enabling our customer&amp;rsquo;s transformation. No appliances need to be provisioned in remote VPCs or VNets, and no agents need to be installed on workloads. Getting started is as easy as kicking off a build pipeline. For Part 2, let&amp;rsquo;s connect some networks from AWS, Azure, and GCP.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Security And Azure Private Link</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cloud-security-and-azure-private-link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 18:55:25 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cloud-security-and-azure-private-link/</guid><description>Azure Private Link enables access to hosted customer and partner services over a private endpoint in an Azure virtual network. This means private connectivity over your own RFC1918 address space to any supported PaaS service while limiting the need for additional gateways, NAT appliances, public IP addresses, or ExpressRoute (Microsoft Peering).
Hold on, wasn&amp;rsquo;t the point of Public Cloud to leverage services offered by third-party providers over the public internet? Why, then, would we want to contain traffic in our private IP space, which is likely routable across our on-premises network?</description></item><item><title>Multi-Cloud Networking With Alkira</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/alkira-multicloud-networking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 13:01:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/alkira-multicloud-networking/</guid><description>Introduction Multi-Cloud is making its rounds. Network and Security engineers face increasing challenges with managing complexity and risk as they work to react with more agility to enable business outcomes. At the start, enterprises didn&amp;rsquo;t just decide they would be multi-cloud. They started with a single cloud, likely Amazon Web Services and tailored their strategy around that cloud&amp;rsquo;s architecture and features.
A little time passes, and now those engineers that are still evolving to handle AWS are tasked with adopting Microsoft Azure.</description></item></channel></rss>