<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 16:47:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Calculating Cost Like a DevOps Boss with Infracost and AWS</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/calculating-cost-like-a-devops-boss-with-infracost-and-aws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 16:47:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/calculating-cost-like-a-devops-boss-with-infracost-and-aws/</guid><description>Blowing out cloud spend is an easy thing to do. This McKinsey Report notes that 80% of enterprises consider managing cloud spend a challenge. I recently presented at the Cloud Security Alliance in Kansas City and had the opportunity to network with some tremendous DevOps and Security professionals. One excellent side conversation somehow transitioned to a deep discussion on better ways to understand cost implications in the era of infrastructure-as-code. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t cost be someone else&amp;rsquo;s problem?</description></item><item><title>The Best Terraform Feature Yet?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 09:55:52 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/</guid><description>Optional attributes for object type constraints is almost here! I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for this feature to come along for a while. I have tested it extensively in -alpha, and I can confidently confirm that it is a game changer. This feature is long in the making, being discussed as far back as this thread in 2018. Today, it is now in beta, so the official release could be any day now.</description></item><item><title>Terraforming Alkira and Fortinet is Multicloud Bliss</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/terraforming-alkira-and-fortinet-is-multicloud-bliss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 13:42:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/terraforming-alkira-and-fortinet-is-multicloud-bliss/</guid><description>There is a reason why enterprises prefer the best-of-breed approach to connect and secure their network and intellectual property. Alkira announced its integration with Fortinet at AWS re:Inforce in July, and this is a perfect example of the best in action. As anyone that reads my blog knows, I have an automation first approach to everything. Alkira&amp;rsquo;s Terraform Provider is Fortinet ready, so let&amp;rsquo;s take it for a spin!
Key Features This partnership comes packed with great features, including the seamless integration of FortiManager (which orchestrates the Fortinet Security Fabric), extending existing firewall zones into and across clouds with auto-mapping of zones-to-groups, and weathering traffic surges with auto-scaling.</description></item><item><title>AWS Community Day - Midwest</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/aws-community-day-midwest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 06:34:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/aws-community-day-midwest/</guid><description>I had the opportunity to present at the 4th annual AWS Community Day for the Midwest in June. This event was planned, organized, and delivered by AWS user group leaders and was an absolute blast. I got to catch up with a few remarkable individuals I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked to since pre-pandemic, and I got to meet many new people and listen to their stories of transformation in their respective enterprises.</description></item><item><title>Exploring ZeroTier For Remote Access</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/exploring-zerotier-for-remote-access/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 12:15:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/exploring-zerotier-for-remote-access/</guid><description>Zero Trust is all the rage lately, and traditional VPNs are getting a lot of scrutiny since they essentially add and remove encryption at the firewall. This means bad actors can skip off into the sunset (laterally) and gain access to those legacy systems with less effort. Another challenge with using a traditional VPN is scaling with the dramatic shift to hybrid work. ZeroTier is an interesting solution that claims to combine the capabilities of VPN and SD-WAN, among other things.</description></item><item><title>Importing Infrastructure With Azure Terrafy</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/importing-infrastructure-with-azure-terrafy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:01:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/importing-infrastructure-with-azure-terrafy/</guid><description>Anyone that has worked in tech knows that building greenfield is much easier than dragging along brownfield environments through a roller-coaster they aren&amp;rsquo;t ready for. Tools like Terraform make infrastructure-as-code a breeze, but what about all that infrastructure you already have provisioned? April Edwards, Cloud Advocate at Microsoft, recently posted a blog about Azure Terrafy, a new tool in preview which aims to simplify the process. You can find the original blog here.</description></item><item><title>Are Microservices Better Than Monoliths?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/are-microservices-better-than-monoliths/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:11:43 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/are-microservices-better-than-monoliths/</guid><description>The year is 2022, and Kubernetes is wreaking havoc on software delivery as we know it. Applications are going through modernization programs so they can be converted into microservices, but they are coming out the other end as distributed monoliths. Next thing you know, services exist across several clouds and even in your data centers. And, of course, the large majority of enterprises aren&amp;rsquo;t just greenfield.
Many have a combination of technologies stacked over decades, including mainframes.</description></item><item><title>Shifting Left with Lightlytics</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/shifting-left-with-lightlytics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 13:04:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2022/shifting-left-with-lightlytics/</guid><description>The public cloud continued to dominate spending in 2021. Gartner forecasts worldwide end-user spending for public cloud to reach $397.4 billion by 2022. With increased velocity; automation continues to be a critical business imperative for the enterprise. Getting automation right means getting all the appropriate teams pulled into the process early on (shift left). Lightlytics is a new SaaS product on the market that aims to make DevOps for cloud infrastructure as agile as software delivery.</description></item><item><title>Cryptocurrency, Energy, and Proof-of-Stake</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cryptocurrency-energy-and-proof-of-stake/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 15:41:42 -0800</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cryptocurrency-energy-and-proof-of-stake/</guid><description>New to cryptocurrency? Check this out for a quick primer. One of the giant debates, often a significant source of criticism, is Bitcoin&amp;rsquo;s energy efficiency (or lack thereof). This criticism may also be expanded to any other currency, or blockchain backed technology that leverages proof-of-work as a consensus mechanism. Innovation is inherent in technology. New ideas, methods, and optimizations come along to take something, add new features, and make it more efficient.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 4)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 15:10:56 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-4/</guid><description>In Part 1, we laid out our foundation. In Part 2 and Part 3 we connected various networks (both cloud and on-premises) and provisioned NGFWs that scale to real-time capacity. By default, networks connected to our corporate segment have full-mesh connectivity to each other. Let&amp;rsquo;s build some policies in code that can work with the groups we created to produce logical micro-segmentation that mirror a few real-world use cases.
Your browser does not support video.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 3)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 07:53:57 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-3/</guid><description>Check out Part 1 and Part 2 where we put together a scalable foundation and connect cloud networks from AWS, Azure, and GCP. For Part 3, we will bring on-premises back into the spotlight and connect some sites over Cisco SD-WAN and IPSEC.
On-premises remains a strong focus for many enterprises through 2021 going into 2022. Some workloads, as noted by Amazon CEO Andy Jassy, may never move to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 2)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 09:26:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we started with a scalable foundation that can adapt over time as the business grows and adjusts to changing markets. With Alkira&amp;rsquo;s Network Cloud, we take a cloud native approach in enabling our customer&amp;rsquo;s transformation. No appliances need to be provisioned in remote VPCs or VNets, and no agents need to be installed on workloads. Getting started is as easy as kicking off a build pipeline. For Part 2, let&amp;rsquo;s connect some networks from AWS, Azure, and GCP.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform - (Part 1)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Sep 2021 08:43:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-1/</guid><description>HashiCorp&amp;rsquo;s Terraform needs no introduction. It is all but the de facto vehicle for delivering cloud infrastructure, and for a good reason. What Terraform did for Multi-Cloud Infrastructure as Code, is precisely what Alkira does for the network. What happens when you use these two platforms together to deliver networking in and across clouds? If providing network services in code faster than ever before sounds interesting, this multi-part series is for you.</description></item><item><title>Intro To Terraform Modules With AWS</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/intro-to-terraform-modules-with-aws/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 08:46:40 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/intro-to-terraform-modules-with-aws/</guid><description>Effectively automating infrastructure is no longer a luxury but a staple in the enterprise move through future transformation. I wrote a blog recently about using Terraform with Packer together, and wanted to take this thought further with breaking down Terraform Modules and getting well connected with Terraform Cloud. I recently put together a simple module for building base infrastructure in AWS for the purpose of testing Alkira Network Cloud. Let&amp;rsquo;s dive in!</description></item><item><title>Understanding The World Of Bitcoin</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/understanding-the-world-of-bitcoin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 17:02:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/understanding-the-world-of-bitcoin/</guid><description>This is going to be a gigantic pivot from my usual topics of writing. If you are interested in learning something about cryptocurrency, stay put. The goal is to make this unbiased and thought-provoking while shedding light on what seems like a world of confusion and misinformation.
In the past month, I have heard various first-hand opinions about Bitcoin like, it is a pyramid scheme, basically gambling, will supersede the U.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Azure Cloud Networking - (Part 2)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/exploring-azure-cloud-networking-part-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 13:11:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/exploring-azure-cloud-networking-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we went over some fundamentals. For Part 2, we will examine Azure network design patterns based on cloud maturity and organization size. The concept of design patterns was first introduced by Christopher Alexander and has profoundly influenced many technical disciplines.
To keep things simple, let&amp;rsquo;s define a design pattern as a reusable solution to a commonly occurring problem. Of course, you are not the first practitioner out there transitioning to cloud or growing to a new maturity model.</description></item><item><title>Exploring Azure Cloud Networking - (Part 1)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/exploring-azure-cloud-networking-part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 14:36:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/exploring-azure-cloud-networking-part-1/</guid><description>Is cloud networking complicated, or is it just different? In building your infrastructure in the cloud, end-to-end system complexity increases exponentially. As enterprise applications mature, the foundational infrastructure and networking used to host and transport them must evolve. One obvious crux of networking is blast radius - you cannot easily modify it without down-time.
This is Part 1 of a multi-part series that will explore Azure networking. To the best of my ability, this series will be written to articulate real-world scenarios and bring attention to specifics that are critical to an understanding before diving into cloud networking architecture.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Grade Automation With Packer and Terraform</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cloud-grade-automation-with-packer-and-terraform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 12:32:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cloud-grade-automation-with-packer-and-terraform/</guid><description>Manually provisioning infrastructure slows down application delivery, isolates knowledge, can hamper operations teams, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale. Automating infrastructure provisioning can address these challenges by shifting manual process into code. Hashicorp has products spanning the infrastructure, security, and application stack that can unlock that cloud operating model and deliver applications faster.
Let&amp;rsquo;s examine image lifecycle management and IaaS deployment. Both of these tasks are common challenges faced by the enterprise when moving to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Security And Azure Private Link</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cloud-security-and-azure-private-link/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 18:55:25 -0500</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2021/cloud-security-and-azure-private-link/</guid><description>Azure Private Link enables access to hosted customer and partner services over a private endpoint in an Azure virtual network. This means private connectivity over your own RFC1918 address space to any supported PaaS service while limiting the need for additional gateways, NAT appliances, public IP addresses, or ExpressRoute (Microsoft Peering).
Hold on, wasn&amp;rsquo;t the point of Public Cloud to leverage services offered by third-party providers over the public internet? Why, then, would we want to contain traffic in our private IP space, which is likely routable across our on-premises network?</description></item><item><title>AnsibleFest 2020 - Automating IPAM In Cloud</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/automating-cloud-ipam/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Oct 2020 07:16:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/automating-cloud-ipam/</guid><description>AnsibleFest 2020, like most conferences this year, took place completely virtual. I presented on Automating IPAM In Cloud: Ansible + Netbox. You can find the slides along with the demonstration code in this git repo. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;m going to expand a little further on the content I presented.
What is IPAM? IP Address Management (IPAM) is the critical component that organizes your IP addresses and networks in one place.</description></item><item><title>Multi-Cloud Networking With Alkira</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/alkira-multicloud-networking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2020 13:01:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/alkira-multicloud-networking/</guid><description>Introduction Multi-Cloud is making its rounds. Network and Security engineers face increasing challenges with managing complexity and risk as they work to react with more agility to enable business outcomes. At the start, enterprises didn&amp;rsquo;t just decide they would be multi-cloud. They started with a single cloud, likely Amazon Web Services and tailored their strategy around that cloud&amp;rsquo;s architecture and features.
A little time passes, and now those engineers that are still evolving to handle AWS are tasked with adopting Microsoft Azure.</description></item><item><title>Automating Blog Releases: Hugo + GitHub Actions</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/automate-blog-deployment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 17:14:44 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/automate-blog-deployment/</guid><description>A lot of the work I do professionally involves transforming traditional network culture, practices, and technology. Just as DevOps transformed application delivery, NetDevOps is here to make sure the network can keep up. This post will cover how I deploy this blog with Hugo to GitHub Pages using GitHub Actions to completely automate the workflow. This is very similar to how I approached modernizing network documentation for my current employer. Listen to Day Two Cloud Podcast as I talk through this transformation in more detail.</description></item><item><title>Setting Up Ansible (AWX) On Debian</title><link>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/setup-awx-on-debian/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2020 12:29:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>http://wcollins.io/post/2020/setup-awx-on-debian/</guid><description>The best way to learn is by constructing your own knowledge, not passively absorbing information. A lot of great projects are open source these days, including The AWX Project. At zero cost, you can build your automation skill set, increasing your chances at landing that next big promotion.
This post will cover how to setup Ansible AWX on Debian. I use a combination of Ansible and Terraform in the NetDevOps toolchain.</description></item></channel></rss>