<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Startups on William Collins</title><link>https://wcollins.io/tags/startups/</link><description>Recent content in Startups on William Collins</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2026 William Collins</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:25:07 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://wcollins.io/tags/startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Ripple Effect: Could Taxing Unrealized Gains Stifle Innovation?</title><link>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:25:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In my &lt;a href="https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer"&gt;previous blog on Dilution of Ownership&lt;/a&gt;, I explored how startup funding rounds impact equity. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into a hot-button, highly-debated, and dramatically misunderstood matter of policy - taxing unrealized capital gains &lt;em&gt;(or the wealth tax)&lt;/em&gt;. Could this policy drastically alter the startup landscape? Would there be a tangible impact on founders, investors, and the innovation ecosystem as a whole?&lt;/p&gt;</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/featured.png"/></item><item><title>Understanding Dilution of Ownership</title><link>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 16:48:03 -0300</pubDate><guid>https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of confusion surrounding the &lt;em&gt;dilution of ownership&lt;/em&gt;, especially in the tech startup space. What does this mean in &lt;em&gt;layman&amp;rsquo;s terms&lt;/em&gt;? Who does it impact? And most importantly, why you should care if you plan to work for a startup. This is a topic I have discussed with many new &lt;em&gt;(and even some seasoned)&lt;/em&gt; engineers over the past few years. I recently had this very discussion with a senior engineer &lt;em&gt;(and close friend)&lt;/em&gt; who is leaving big enterprise for startup land. He suggested I write a blog in the &lt;em&gt;plain speak&lt;/em&gt; that I used with him. Little does he know (until now) that this is as deep as I go on this topic!&lt;/p&gt;</description><media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/featured.png"/></item></channel></rss>