<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>transit-gateway - Tag - Blog</title><link>http://wcollins.io/tags/transit-gateway/</link><description>transit-gateway - Tag - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 08:54:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/tags/transit-gateway/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS DC Summit - Recap</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/aws-dc-summit-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 08:54:11 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/aws-dc-summit-recap/</guid><description>What fits somewhere in between re:Invent and Community Day events? That would be the AWS Summits! This year, I got to experience a double dose of fun by representing Alkira at our booth and presenting at the AWS Community Developer Lounge. I may be biased, but I believe the Alkira team is the best in the world.
It was a blast getting to talk about cloud networking with event attendees while getting a glimpse of how the public sector is adapting to change.</description></item><item><title>Evolution of AWS Site-to-Site VPN - Part 2</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/evolution-of-aws-site-to-site-vpn-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 16:16:25 -0500</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/evolution-of-aws-site-to-site-vpn-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we talked about the origins of the Site-to-Site VPN Service in AWS. As consumers began to scale in the early days, they faced tunnel sprawl, performance constraints, and the need for a simplified design. AWS responded with Transit Gateway. How did Transit Gateway simplify architecture leading to smoother operations, better network performance, and a scalable blueprint for the future network?
Intro Pre Transit Gateway Security teams in the early days would often balk at the idea of using VPC peering without having a centralized transit hub (where the hybrid connectivity was landed).</description></item></channel></rss>