<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>tools - Category - Blog</title><link>http://wcollins.io/categories/tools/</link><description>tools - Category - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 12:03:15 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/categories/tools/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Configuring Systems With ChatGPT, Python, and Go</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/configuring-systems-with-chatgpt-python-and-go/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 12:03:15 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/configuring-systems-with-chatgpt-python-and-go/</guid><description>I recently wrote a blog about generating Terraform with ChatGPT. In that experiment, I was using GPT-3.5. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take much to trip up the galactic AI in many of the experiments I did with Terraform and beyond. According to OpenAI GPT-4 soars past its predecessor in its advanced reasoning capabilities. Let&amp;rsquo;s use this model to build code in Python and Go. How will the super titan fair in the Sysadmin arena?</description></item><item><title>Can ChatGPT Terraform Simple Networking In AWS?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/can-chatgpt-terraform-simple-networking-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 09:31:12 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/can-chatgpt-terraform-simple-networking-in-aws/</guid><description>Usually, when it comes to technology, my grandmother doesn&amp;rsquo;t know much because she doesn&amp;rsquo;t care. What is the cloud? How to install a new browser on her laptop? What is 2FA? I might be speaking French to her as I discuss these things. Yet, she knows what ChatGPT is. This shows the vast amount of publicity, hype, and polarization that has ensued since November 2022. I tend to avoid AI fear-mongering and focus more on, how could a tool like this help enhance my daily grind?</description></item><item><title>Calculating Cost Like a DevOps Boss with Infracost and AWS</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/calculating-cost-like-a-devops-boss-with-infracost-and-aws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 16:47:40 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/calculating-cost-like-a-devops-boss-with-infracost-and-aws/</guid><description>Blowing out cloud spend is an easy thing to do. This McKinsey Report notes that 80% of enterprises consider managing cloud spend a challenge. I recently presented at the Cloud Security Alliance in Kansas City and had the opportunity to network with some tremendous DevOps and Security professionals. One excellent side conversation somehow transitioned to a deep discussion on better ways to understand cost implications in the era of infrastructure-as-code. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t cost be someone else&amp;rsquo;s problem?</description></item><item><title>The Best Terraform Feature Yet?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 09:55:52 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/</guid><description>Optional attributes for object type constraints is almost here! I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for this feature to come along for a while. I have tested it extensively in -alpha, and I can confidently confirm that it is a game changer. This feature is long in the making, being discussed as far back as this thread in 2018. Today, it is now in beta, so the official release could be any day now.</description></item><item><title>Importing Infrastructure With Azure Terrafy</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/importing-infrastructure-with-azure-terrafy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:01:11 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/importing-infrastructure-with-azure-terrafy/</guid><description>Anyone that has worked in tech knows that building greenfield is much easier than dragging along brownfield environments through a roller-coaster they aren&amp;rsquo;t ready for. Tools like Terraform make infrastructure-as-code a breeze, but what about all that infrastructure you already have provisioned? April Edwards, Cloud Advocate at Microsoft, recently posted a blog about Azure Terrafy, a new tool in preview which aims to simplify the process. You can find the original blog here.</description></item><item><title>Are Microservices Better Than Monoliths?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/are-microservices-better-than-monoliths/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 07:11:43 -0500</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/are-microservices-better-than-monoliths/</guid><description>The year is 2022, and Kubernetes is wreaking havoc on software delivery as we know it. Applications are going through modernization programs so they can be converted into microservices, but they are coming out the other end as distributed monoliths. Next thing you know, services exist across several clouds and even in your data centers. And, of course, the large majority of enterprises aren&amp;rsquo;t just greenfield.
Many have a combination of technologies stacked over decades, including mainframes.</description></item><item><title>Shifting Left with Lightlytics</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/shifting-left-with-lightlytics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 13:04:48 -0500</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/shifting-left-with-lightlytics/</guid><description>The public cloud continued to dominate spending in 2021. Gartner forecasts worldwide end-user spending for public cloud to reach $397.4 billion by 2022. With increased velocity; automation continues to be a critical business imperative for the enterprise. Getting automation right means getting all the appropriate teams pulled into the process early on (shift left). Lightlytics is a new SaaS product on the market that aims to make DevOps for cloud infrastructure as agile as software delivery.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 4)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-4/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 15:10:56 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-4/</guid><description>In Part 1, we laid out our foundation. In Part 2 and Part 3 we connected various networks (both cloud and on-premises) and provisioned NGFWs that scale to real-time capacity. By default, networks connected to our corporate segment have full-mesh connectivity to each other. Let&amp;rsquo;s build some policies in code that can work with the groups we created to produce logical micro-segmentation that mirror a few real-world use cases.
Your browser does not support video.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 3)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 07:53:57 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-3/</guid><description>Check out Part 1 and Part 2 where we put together a scalable foundation and connect cloud networks from AWS, Azure, and GCP. For Part 3, we will bring on-premises back into the spotlight and connect some sites over Cisco SD-WAN and IPSEC.
On-premises remains a strong focus for many enterprises through 2021 going into 2022. Some workloads, as noted by Amazon CEO Andy Jassy, may never move to the cloud.</description></item><item><title>Getting Started With Alkira And Terraform (Part 2)</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 09:26:46 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2021/getting-started-with-alkira-and-terraform-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we started with a scalable foundation that can adapt over time as the business grows and adjusts to changing markets. With Alkira&amp;rsquo;s Network Cloud, we take a cloud native approach in enabling our customer&amp;rsquo;s transformation. No appliances need to be provisioned in remote VPCs or VNets, and no agents need to be installed on workloads. Getting started is as easy as kicking off a build pipeline. For Part 2, let&amp;rsquo;s connect some networks from AWS, Azure, and GCP.</description></item></channel></rss>