<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - Blog</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/</link><description>All Posts | Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 12:05:44 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tesla Adapts Ethernet with Modified Transport Layer for Dojo</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/tesla-adapts-ethernet-for-with-modified-transport-for-dojo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 12:05:44 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/tesla-adapts-ethernet-for-with-modified-transport-for-dojo/</guid><description>The foundation of high-performance computing that powers artificial intelligence lies not just in powerful GPUs, but in the intricate web of connections between them. As models grow exponentially in size and complexity, the networking infrastructure that facilitates their training has become a critical bottleneck. This has sparked a fascinating race to develop networking solutions tailored for AI-centric workloads, with tech giants like NVIDIA who are on an infrastructure trailblazing marathon.</description></item><item><title>The Ripple Effect: Could Taxing Unrealized Gains Stifle Innovation?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 14:25:07 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/taxing-unrealized-gains/</guid><description>In my previous blog on Dilution of Ownership, I explored how startup funding rounds impact equity. Now, let&amp;rsquo;s dive into a hot-button, highly-debated, and dramatically misunderstood matter of policy - taxing unrealized capital gains (or the wealth tax). Could this policy drastically alter the startup landscape? Would there be a tangible impact on founders, investors, and the innovation ecosystem as a whole?
Intro The Allure of Taxing Paper WealthOn the surface, taxing unrealized gains - (the increase in value of an asset that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been sold yet) - might seem like a fair way to ensure the ultra-wealthy pay their &amp;ldquo;fair share.</description></item><item><title>Understanding Dilution of Ownership</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 16:48:03 -0300</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/understanding-dilution-of-ownership/</guid><description>There is a lot of confusion surrounding the dilution of ownership, especially in the tech startup space. What does this mean in layman&amp;rsquo;s terms? Who does it impact? And most importantly, why you should care if you plan to work for a startup. This is a topic I have discussed with many new (and even some seasoned) engineers over the past few years. I recently had this very discussion with a senior engineer (and close friend) who is leaving big enterprise for startup land.</description></item><item><title>GCP SDK Fun</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/gcp-sdk-fun/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 16:48:03 -0500</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2024/gcp-sdk-fun/</guid><description>Sometimes, especially if you aren&amp;rsquo;t a developer by trade, you can get stuck on something small that will find you banging your forehead on your desk (figuratively, of course). Most of the time, it is easy enough to find an answer online or even from ChatGPT. Other times, you may not be so lucky. The other day, I fell victim to a TWE or time wasting event that I thought was worth writing about.</description></item><item><title>Using Terraform Import Blocks with Alkira</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/using-terraform-import-blocks-with-alkira/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2023 14:37:36 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/using-terraform-import-blocks-with-alkira/</guid><description>For many moons, importing existing infrastructure (that is to say, infrastructure running outside of Terraform state), has not been a trivial task. Historically, Terraform did not generate any configuration. You would have to write the infrastructure-as-code in a manner that reflects how it was deployed. Then, to make matters not easier, you would fetch the &amp;lsquo;ol shovel and dig out the unique resource identifiers to feed through the command line. Handling a single resource in this manner is pretty simple.</description></item><item><title>AWS DC Summit - Recap</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/aws-dc-summit-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 08:54:11 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/aws-dc-summit-recap/</guid><description>What fits somewhere in between re:Invent and Community Day events? That would be the AWS Summits! This year, I got to experience a double dose of fun by representing Alkira at our booth and presenting at the AWS Community Developer Lounge. I may be biased, but I believe the Alkira team is the best in the world.
It was a blast getting to talk about cloud networking with event attendees while getting a glimpse of how the public sector is adapting to change.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Systems With ChatGPT, Python, and Go</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/configuring-systems-with-chatgpt-python-and-go/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 12:03:15 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/configuring-systems-with-chatgpt-python-and-go/</guid><description>I recently wrote a blog about generating Terraform with ChatGPT. In that experiment, I was using GPT-3.5. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take much to trip up the galactic AI in many of the experiments I did with Terraform and beyond. According to OpenAI GPT-4 soars past its predecessor in its advanced reasoning capabilities. Let&amp;rsquo;s use this model to build code in Python and Go. How will the super titan fair in the Sysadmin arena?</description></item><item><title>Can ChatGPT Terraform Simple Networking In AWS?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/can-chatgpt-terraform-simple-networking-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 09:31:12 -0400</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/can-chatgpt-terraform-simple-networking-in-aws/</guid><description>Usually, when it comes to technology, my grandmother doesn&amp;rsquo;t know much because she doesn&amp;rsquo;t care. What is the cloud? How to install a new browser on her laptop? What is 2FA? I might be speaking French to her as I discuss these things. Yet, she knows what ChatGPT is. This shows the vast amount of publicity, hype, and polarization that has ensued since November 2022. I tend to avoid AI fear-mongering and focus more on, how could a tool like this help enhance my daily grind?</description></item><item><title>Evolution of AWS Site-to-Site VPN - Part 2</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/evolution-of-aws-site-to-site-vpn-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 16:16:25 -0500</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/evolution-of-aws-site-to-site-vpn-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we talked about the origins of the Site-to-Site VPN Service in AWS. As consumers began to scale in the early days, they faced tunnel sprawl, performance constraints, and the need for a simplified design. AWS responded with Transit Gateway. How did Transit Gateway simplify architecture leading to smoother operations, better network performance, and a scalable blueprint for the future network?
Intro Pre Transit GatewaySecurity teams in the early days would often balk at the idea of using VPC peering without having a centralized transit hub (where the hybrid connectivity was landed).</description></item><item><title>Looking Back At 2022</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/looking-back-at-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 14:25:04 -0500</pubDate><author><name>William Collins</name></author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/looking-back-at-2022/</guid><description>At the end of each year, I take some time for self-reflection. Looking back through 2022 gave me a colossal reminder of how vital teams, communities, and leaders are. Take hockey for instance. You have certain athletes, often referred to as generational players that carry unmatched individual talent and get selected first overall in the NHL Draft.
These players are weekly highlight reels, yet, without the right system, coaches, and team, they will never lift the Stanley Cup.</description></item></channel></rss>