<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>github actions - Tag - Blog</title><link>http://wcollins.io/tags/github-actions/</link><description>github actions - Tag - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 16:47:40 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/tags/github-actions/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Calculating Cost Like a DevOps Boss with Infracost and AWS</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/calculating-cost-like-a-devops-boss-with-infracost-and-aws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 16:47:40 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/calculating-cost-like-a-devops-boss-with-infracost-and-aws/</guid><description>Blowing out cloud spend is an easy thing to do. This McKinsey Report notes that 80% of enterprises consider managing cloud spend a challenge. I recently presented at the Cloud Security Alliance in Kansas City and had the opportunity to network with some tremendous DevOps and Security professionals. One excellent side conversation somehow transitioned to a deep discussion on better ways to understand cost implications in the era of infrastructure-as-code. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t cost be someone else&amp;rsquo;s problem?</description></item><item><title>Shifting Left with Lightlytics</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/shifting-left-with-lightlytics/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 13:04:48 -0500</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/shifting-left-with-lightlytics/</guid><description>The public cloud continued to dominate spending in 2021. Gartner forecasts worldwide end-user spending for public cloud to reach $397.4 billion by 2022. With increased velocity; automation continues to be a critical business imperative for the enterprise. Getting automation right means getting all the appropriate teams pulled into the process early on (shift left). Lightlytics is a new SaaS product on the market that aims to make DevOps for cloud infrastructure as agile as software delivery.</description></item><item><title>Automating Blog Releases: Hugo + GitHub Actions</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2020/automate-blog-deployment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 17:14:44 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2020/automate-blog-deployment/</guid><description>A lot of the work I do professionally involves transforming traditional network culture, practices, and technology. Just as DevOps transformed application delivery, NetDevOps is here to make sure the network can keep up. This post will cover how I deploy this blog with Hugo to GitHub Pages using GitHub Actions to completely automate the workflow. This is very similar to how I approached modernizing network documentation for my current employer. Listen to Day Two Cloud Podcast as I talk through this transformation in more detail.</description></item></channel></rss>