<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>cloud - Category - Blog</title><link>http://wcollins.io/categories/cloud/</link><description>cloud - Category - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 08:54:11 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://wcollins.io/categories/cloud/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>AWS DC Summit - Recap</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/aws-dc-summit-recap/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 08:54:11 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/aws-dc-summit-recap/</guid><description>What fits somewhere in between re:Invent and Community Day events? That would be the AWS Summits! This year, I got to experience a double dose of fun by representing Alkira at our booth and presenting at the AWS Community Developer Lounge. I may be biased, but I believe the Alkira team is the best in the world.
It was a blast getting to talk about cloud networking with event attendees while getting a glimpse of how the public sector is adapting to change.</description></item><item><title>Configuring Systems With ChatGPT, Python, and Go</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/configuring-systems-with-chatgpt-python-and-go/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 12:03:15 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/configuring-systems-with-chatgpt-python-and-go/</guid><description>I recently wrote a blog about generating Terraform with ChatGPT. In that experiment, I was using GPT-3.5. It didn&amp;rsquo;t take much to trip up the galactic AI in many of the experiments I did with Terraform and beyond. According to OpenAI GPT-4 soars past its predecessor in its advanced reasoning capabilities. Let&amp;rsquo;s use this model to build code in Python and Go. How will the super titan fair in the Sysadmin arena?</description></item><item><title>Can ChatGPT Terraform Simple Networking In AWS?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/can-chatgpt-terraform-simple-networking-in-aws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 09:31:12 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/can-chatgpt-terraform-simple-networking-in-aws/</guid><description>Usually, when it comes to technology, my grandmother doesn&amp;rsquo;t know much because she doesn&amp;rsquo;t care. What is the cloud? How to install a new browser on her laptop? What is 2FA? I might be speaking French to her as I discuss these things. Yet, she knows what ChatGPT is. This shows the vast amount of publicity, hype, and polarization that has ensued since November 2022. I tend to avoid AI fear-mongering and focus more on, how could a tool like this help enhance my daily grind?</description></item><item><title>Evolution of AWS Site-to-Site VPN - Part 2</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/evolution-of-aws-site-to-site-vpn-part-2/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 16:16:25 -0500</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2023/evolution-of-aws-site-to-site-vpn-part-2/</guid><description>In Part 1, we talked about the origins of the Site-to-Site VPN Service in AWS. As consumers began to scale in the early days, they faced tunnel sprawl, performance constraints, and the need for a simplified design. AWS responded with Transit Gateway. How did Transit Gateway simplify architecture leading to smoother operations, better network performance, and a scalable blueprint for the future network?
Intro Pre Transit Gateway Security teams in the early days would often balk at the idea of using VPC peering without having a centralized transit hub (where the hybrid connectivity was landed).</description></item><item><title>Looking Back At 2022</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/looking-back-at-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2022 14:25:04 -0500</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/looking-back-at-2022/</guid><description>At the end of each year, I take some time for self-reflection. Looking back through 2022 gave me a colossal reminder of how vital teams, communities, and leaders are. Take hockey for instance. You have certain athletes, often referred to as generational players that carry unmatched individual talent and get selected first overall in the NHL Draft.
These players are weekly highlight reels, yet, without the right system, coaches, and team, they will never lift the Stanley Cup.</description></item><item><title>Evolution of AWS Site-to-Site VPN - Part 1</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/evolution-of-aws-site-to-site-vpn-part-1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2022 08:15:58 -0500</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/evolution-of-aws-site-to-site-vpn-part-1/</guid><description>The necessity for protocols to keep communication secure has been around since the dawn of the internet. The first ever VPN was jointly developed by a vendor consortium (which included Microsoft) in 1996, and came in the form of Point-to-Point Tunneling Protocol. Although many are skeptical about the value of VPNs in 2022 and beyond, customer consumption of cloud provider VPN services have paved the way for additional features and exponential scale.</description></item><item><title>Calculating Cost Like a DevOps Boss with Infracost and AWS</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/calculating-cost-like-a-devops-boss-with-infracost-and-aws/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 16:47:40 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/calculating-cost-like-a-devops-boss-with-infracost-and-aws/</guid><description>Blowing out cloud spend is an easy thing to do. This McKinsey Report notes that 80% of enterprises consider managing cloud spend a challenge. I recently presented at the Cloud Security Alliance in Kansas City and had the opportunity to network with some tremendous DevOps and Security professionals. One excellent side conversation somehow transitioned to a deep discussion on better ways to understand cost implications in the era of infrastructure-as-code. Shouldn&amp;rsquo;t cost be someone else&amp;rsquo;s problem?</description></item><item><title>The Best Terraform Feature Yet?</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 09:55:52 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/the-best-terraform-feature-yet/</guid><description>Optional attributes for object type constraints is almost here! I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for this feature to come along for a while. I have tested it extensively in -alpha, and I can confidently confirm that it is a game changer. This feature is long in the making, being discussed as far back as this thread in 2018. Today, it is now in beta, so the official release could be any day now.</description></item><item><title>Terraforming Alkira and Fortinet is Multicloud Bliss</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/terraforming-alkira-and-fortinet-is-multicloud-bliss/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 13:42:35 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/terraforming-alkira-and-fortinet-is-multicloud-bliss/</guid><description>There is a reason why enterprises prefer the best-of-breed approach to connect and secure their network and intellectual property. Alkira announced its integration with Fortinet at AWS re:Inforce in July, and this is a perfect example of the best in action. As anyone that reads my blog knows, I have an automation first approach to everything. Alkira&amp;rsquo;s Terraform Provider is Fortinet ready, so let&amp;rsquo;s take it for a spin!
Intro Key Features This partnership comes packed with great features, including the seamless integration of FortiManager (which orchestrates the Fortinet Security Fabric), extending existing firewall zones into and across clouds with auto-mapping of zones-to-groups, and weathering traffic surges with auto-scaling.</description></item><item><title>Importing Infrastructure With Azure Terrafy</title><link>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/importing-infrastructure-with-azure-terrafy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 08:01:11 -0400</pubDate><author>William Collins</author><guid>http://wcollins.io/posts/2022/importing-infrastructure-with-azure-terrafy/</guid><description>Anyone that has worked in tech knows that building greenfield is much easier than dragging along brownfield environments through a roller-coaster they aren&amp;rsquo;t ready for. Tools like Terraform make infrastructure-as-code a breeze, but what about all that infrastructure you already have provisioned? April Edwards, Cloud Advocate at Microsoft, recently posted a blog about Azure Terrafy, a new tool in preview which aims to simplify the process. You can find the original blog here.</description></item></channel></rss>